<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A modest answer to Captain Smith's immodest memoirs of secret service and his remarks upon the D. of S---'s letter to the House of Lords humbly dedicated to the Right Honourable, the Lords spiritual and temporal in Parliament assembled by Ric. Kingston.</title>
            <author>Kingston, Richard, b. 1635?</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 55 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 22 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A47483</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing K613</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R28760</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">10758617</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 10758617</idno>
            <idno type="VID">45670</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A47483)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 45670)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1405:34)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A modest answer to Captain Smith's immodest memoirs of secret service and his remarks upon the D. of S---'s letter to the House of Lords humbly dedicated to the Right Honourable, the Lords spiritual and temporal in Parliament assembled by Ric. Kingston.</title>
                  <author>Kingston, Richard, b. 1635?</author>
                  <author>Smith, Matthew, fl. 1696. Memoirs of secret service.</author>
                  <author>Smith, Matthew, fl. 1696. Remarks upon the D--. of S-----'s letter to the House of Lords concerning Captain Smyth.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>43 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for John Nutt,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Union Theological Seminary Library, New York.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Jacobites.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  1660-1714.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:45670:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A MODEST ANSWER TO Captain <hi>SMITH</hi>'s Immodeſt MEMOIRS OF <hi>Secret Service.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>AND HIS REMARKS UPON THE D. of <hi>S</hi>—'s Letter, TO THE Houſe of LORDS.</p>
            <p>Humbly Dedicated to the Right Honourable The Lords <hi>Spiritual</hi> and <hi>Temporal,</hi> In Parliament Aſſembled.</p>
            <p>By <hi>RIC. KINGSTON.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>John Nutt,</hi> near <hi>Stationers-Hall,</hi> 1700.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:45670:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:45670:2"/>
            <head>A Modeſt Anſwer TO Captain <hi>SMITH</hi>'s Immodeſt Memoirs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THO' the <hi>Juſtice</hi> of the Right Honourable the Houſe of <hi>Peers</hi> in their Proceedings a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt Captain <hi>Matthew Smith,</hi> has given an Intire Satisfaction to all, that by examining the Stratagem, have diſcovered that the bottom of the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign in Publiſhing his <hi>Two Books,</hi> was meerly the Contrivance of a <hi>Party</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt a Perſon of <hi>Great Honour and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tegrity;</hi> yet becauſe others, that either being in the <hi>Party</hi> that put the <hi>Unthink<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:45670:3"/>
Captain, upon ſo Rude an Enter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prize, or that take every thing for <hi>Truth</hi> that they deſire ſhould be thought ſo, are ſtill Whiſpering their Diſcon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents, and Buzzing it from Ear to Ear, that the Captain has very hard Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure; I thought fit to rectify that <hi>Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtake,</hi> and ſet the whole Affair in its pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per light: Not as a Buſy Intermedler in Publick Affairs, but as a Friend to <hi>Truth</hi> and <hi>Juſtice,</hi> that having it in his Power to <hi>Diſabuſe</hi> the Nation, thinks it his indiſpenſible Duty not to neglect this Opportunity of doing it.</p>
            <p>The Author is ſo perfect a <hi>Stranger</hi> to his <hi>Grace</hi> the D. of <hi>S.</hi> that he never had the Honour of Speaking to him but once in his Life, and that is now about Three Years ago, and 'twould be a grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter piece of Diſingenuity, than he can believe any Man will be guilty of, to inſinuate that the Author is making his <hi>Court</hi> to the D. by this diſcovery of the Artifice, that has been employed to Aſperſe his known <hi>Honour</hi> and <hi>Fide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Nor has he any Intention to Leſſen Captain <hi>Smith</hi>'s Services, or hinder him from the <hi>Juſt Reward</hi> that is due to them, by making Reflections upon his Perſon or Converſation, any further than the
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:45670:3"/>
neceſſity of ſpeaking Truth extorts them from him, nor will advance any thing in Confutation of his Books, or Detecting his Criminal Confederacy, but from apparent Matters of Fact, and Irreproachable Evidence.</p>
            <p>I am not ignorant that this Narration is <hi>Impar Congreſſus,</hi> for which I humbly beg his <hi>Graces</hi> Pardon, and intreat the Reader in <hi>Honour</hi> to make that <hi>Allowance</hi> through the whole Diſcourſe; but if any think fit to <hi>Chide</hi> the Undertaking upon that Conſideration, (having already con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſt my Fault) I have only this Boon to ask; That they would ſuſpend their Cenſure till they have Read the Book, and then a God's Name let them ſpeak their Pleaſure.</p>
            <p>To proceed orderly in this Affair, I am obliged to acquaint my Reader, that tho' Captain <hi>Smith</hi>'s Letters of <hi>Corre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpondence</hi> with his <hi>Grace</hi> the D. of <hi>S,</hi> had been long transfer'd from Hand to Hand in Manuſcripts; yet the Printing and Publiſhing them under the Title of <hi>Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moirs of Secret Service,</hi> raiſing all the Clamour and Noiſe, that has been made about them ſince; it will be neceſſary in laying open the Deſign againſt his <hi>Grace,</hi> and diſcovering the Captain's Practices, to begin with that Book.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:45670:4"/>And herein I will prove.</p>
            <p>Firſt, Tho' Captain <hi>Smith</hi> with great Aſſurance, has Printed his Name in the Title-Page of thoſe <hi>Memoirs,</hi> as Author of the Book; <hi>It was not written by him.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Secondly, That the Writing, and Gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving away Five Hundred of thoſe Books, Publiſhing and Maintaining the Captain, and the Perſon that Wrote it, was carri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed on by a <hi>Contribution, at the Charge of a Party.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Thirdly, That the very <hi>Letters</hi> of the Captain's Correſpondence, as now Printed in the <hi>Memoirs,</hi> are ſo Alter'd, and in them are ſo many Additions, Spu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious Gloſſes, and Artificial Connexions, that they cannot be ſaid to be the ſame with the Originals ſent to the D, and conſequently, that no Inferences can or ought to be collected from them, to ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port Captain <hi>Smith</hi>'s Pretenſions againſt him.</p>
            <p>Fourthly, That the Subſtance of both his Books, generally ſpeaking, are meer Fardles of <hi>Improbabilities, Incongruities, and Invented Falſities.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And having diſpatch'd an Anſwer to the Firſt, I ſhall proceed to this <hi>Second Book,</hi> Entituled, <hi>Remarks upon the D.
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:45670:4"/>
of</hi> S—<hi>'s Letter concerning Captain</hi> Smith, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Book</hi> claim'd by Captain <hi>Smith,</hi> Entituled, <hi>Memoirs of Secret Service,</hi> was Written by Mr. <hi>Thomas Brown,</hi> a Stiff <hi>Jacobite,</hi> and a Mercenary <hi>Poet,</hi> that will Write any thing, or againſt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Man for <hi>Money.</hi> And here methinks Captain <hi>Smith,</hi> that pretends to be ſo <hi>ſtout</hi> a <hi>Williamite,</hi> has made a Horrible Blunder in his <hi>Politicks,</hi> at the Threſhold of his Enterprize, in employing a <hi>Rank Proſtituted</hi> Jacobite, <hi>to do</hi> (as he calls it) <hi>Service for the Government;</hi> and I can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not get over the <hi>Aenigma,</hi> without the Aſſiſtance of a Proverb, <hi>Like to like</hi>— Tho ſome will applaud his Judgment in the choice of ſuch a <hi>Tool;</hi> for deſign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to <hi>Calumniate</hi> an <hi>Eminent Miniſter,</hi> who was ſo fit to undertake it, as a <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bauch'd and Mercenary</hi> Jacobite, <hi>whoſe pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culiar Talent lies in Scandalizing Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kind.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Sheet of the firſt Impreſſion of theſe <hi>Memoirs,</hi> by a Miſtake, coming to me to be <hi>Corrected,</hi> gave me the firſt Opportunity of <hi>Gueſſing</hi> at the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thor.</p>
            <p>Reading the <hi>Preface,</hi> the <hi>Paraphraſe,</hi> the <hi>Obſervations,</hi> and the <hi>Minutes,</hi> which almoſt compoſe the whole Pamphlet:
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:45670:5"/>
And meeting a Quotation in <hi>Latine</hi> from <hi>Titus Livius,</hi> to which <hi>Language</hi> I knew Captain <hi>Smith</hi> ſo perfect a Stranger, that he familiarly breaks <hi>Priſcian</hi>'s Head in <hi>Engliſh:</hi> And knowing that he is no more able to Write one <hi>Line</hi> of that <hi>Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>face,</hi> than to run away with the <hi>Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nument,</hi> confirm'd my Opinion, that Mr. <hi>Brown</hi> was the Author of it. Now</p>
            <p>Reſolving to make my ſelf <hi>Maſter</hi> of the Secret, I ſent for Mr. <hi>Brown</hi> to me. At his coming, I charg'd him with the Fact; ſhew'd him the Infamy and Dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger of the Action, and he immediately confeſs'd, <hi>He was the Author of the Book,</hi> Entituled, <hi>Memoirs of Secret Service;</hi> Curs'd Captain <hi>Smith,</hi> for drawing him into a Snare, and employing his Pen to ſo <hi>Baſe a purpoſe,</hi> for which, he ſaid, he heartily Beg'd the D's Pardon; and by way of <hi>Atonement,</hi> voluntarily offer'd <hi>to tell me all he knew in the Matter.</hi> Theſe Words were ſpoken in the Preſence and Hearing of Mr. <hi>M. S.</hi> Phyſician, Mr. <hi>A. R.</hi> Bookſeller, and Mr. <hi>B. B.</hi> Printer.</p>
            <p>At another time diſcourſing this Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject with Mr. <hi>Brown,</hi> in the Preſence of Mr. <hi>A. R.</hi> he told us how bravely he Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved, while he was Writing the Book
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:45670:5"/>
before-mentioned; and that when he had <hi>finiſhed the Copy for the Preſs,</hi> and Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain <hi>Smith</hi> being then out of Pocket, and expecting no great Sum of Money till the Sitting of the <hi>Parliament, he gave him a Bill under his Hand for the Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Fifty Pounds for Writing that Book.</hi> And now having proved this Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular beyond Diſpute, I proceed to my Second Head; which is,</p>
            <p>That Writing, Publiſhing, and Giv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing away above Five Hundred of theſe <hi>Memoirs,</hi> and the Charge of Maintain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the <hi>Captain</hi> and the <hi>Poet,</hi> while he was Writing the Book, was carried on by a <hi>Contribution,</hi> at the Charge of a <hi>Party.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>For Proof of this Particular, I muſt again make uſe of Mr. <hi>Brown,</hi> who at the ſame Place, and Time, and before Mr. <hi>A. R.</hi> above-named, told it me, in the very Words they are inſerted in a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove. He alſo added the Names of ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Conſiderable Perſons that were Contributers to the <hi>Charge,</hi> which I think is neither Safe nor Prudent in me to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>member: And alſo that <hi>Dr.</hi> Chamber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lain, <hi>who lives in</hi> Suffolk-Street, (to uſe <hi>Brown</hi>'s own Words) <hi>was Caſheer to the Party, and ſent Money to Captain</hi> Smith
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:45670:6"/>
               <hi>by his Foot-Boy, as often as the Captain ſent for it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Having travell'd ſo far, and ſucceſs<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully in this Affair, and my Curioſity tempting me to poſſeſs my ſelf of the whole Matter, I ſoon perceived what I had long ſuſpected, and now am obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged to prove as my Third Particular, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That the very Letters of Captain <hi>Smith</hi>'s Correſpondence with his <hi>Grace</hi> the D. of <hi>S,</hi> as now Printed in the <hi>Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moirs,</hi> are in many Places alter'd, and ſo many Gloſſes and Artificial Connexi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons added to them, that they cannot be ſaid <hi>to be the ſame with the Originals ſent to the D,</hi> and conſequently that no Infe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rences can or ought to be collected from them, to ſupport <hi>Smith</hi>'s Pretenſions a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt him.</p>
            <p>Captain <hi>Smith</hi> in <hi>April</hi> 1696, deliver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed all the Copies of his Letters of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſpondence with his <hi>Grace</hi> into my Hands; and now upon reading the Book, finding thoſe in <hi>Print</hi> run ſmoo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and that they were more intelligi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly connected, than any I had read that were Written by Captain <hi>Smith</hi> himſelf, without the help of a <hi>Prompter,</hi> I began to ſuſpect ſome <hi>Foul Play, or Trick,</hi> was in the Wind. I diligently compared the
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:45670:6"/>
               <hi>Written</hi> and <hi>Printed</hi> Letters, and ſoon found <hi>tho' they are bad enough ſtill,</hi> that the Finger of <hi>Tom Brown</hi> had been there; for ſeveral Paſſages are added to thoſe in <hi>Print,</hi> that were not in his firſt <hi>Written</hi> Copies. Some <hi>flat</hi> Words were chang<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for <hi>better;</hi> and in other Places <hi>whole Sentences Alter'd,</hi> to mend the Sence, to ſmooth the Cadencies, <hi>and to make them ſpeak more to his purpoſe in Print, than they did in Manuſcript.</hi> This I thought ſufficient to deſtroy all his Pretences to Veracity.</p>
            <p>However, becauſe this Proof, tho' as plain as <hi>Demonſtration</hi> to my ſelf, yet was liable to Exceptions by thoſe that favour'd the Perſon and aſſiſted the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trivance.</p>
            <p>I enquired from whoſe <hi>Hand-Writing</hi> the Letters were Printed off; and being aſſured it was done from Captain <hi>Smith</hi>'s Hand-Writing, to ſave the trouble of Tranſcribing, I procured the Copy to be left with me, by which I ſoon per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, tho' the Letters were Written in <hi>Smith</hi>'s Hand, yet they were in ſeveral Places <hi>Corrected, Mended, Alter'd, and ſeveral Additions</hi> made to them, by <hi>blot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting</hi> out what had been Written by the <hi>Captain,</hi> and Interlineations and Additi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons made in Mr. <hi>Brown</hi>'s <hi>Hand,</hi> and the
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:45670:7"/>
difference between the <hi>two Hands</hi> as plain to be ſeen, as the Noſe on either of their Faces: And reſolving not to be ſingle in the knowledge of this <hi>Artifice,</hi> I ſhewed the <hi>Copy with the Additions and Altera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions to a Miniſter of</hi> State; who, if there be occaſion, I am ſure will do me Juſtice in what I have aſſerted.</p>
            <p>Still methinks I hear <hi>ſome Body</hi> en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire, How I came by the <hi>Blotted</hi> and <hi>Interlined Copy?</hi> I Anſwer:</p>
            <p>It was delivered into my Hands by the <hi>Bookſeller</hi> and <hi>Printer,</hi> when the firſt Impreſſion was Printing off; and I be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that <hi>very Copy</hi> is yet in my power to produce, if required to do it.</p>
            <p>After this, having an Opportunity to Diſcourſe Mr. <hi>Brown,</hi> I charg'd him with making the Alterations and Additions a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid. He would fain have <hi>ſhuffled</hi> it off at firſt; but when he heard me ſay, <hi>I would ſhew him his own Hand in the Copy to prove it.</hi> He anſwer'd:</p>
            <p>
               <hi>What wou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d you have me do?</hi> Smith <hi>cannot Write Senſe; and I having Wrote the Preface, made Obſervations, and lick'd over his Minutes, I was forc'd to ſtick in here and there a Word, and now and then Uſher in a ſhort</hi> Sentence <hi>to make his Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters ſpeak</hi> Sence, <hi>and ſeem of a piece with the reſt; for which Captain</hi> Smith <hi>promi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:45670:7"/>
to bear me Harmleſs.</hi> This was ſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken in the preſence of Mr. <hi>J. H.</hi> and Mr. <hi>T. W.</hi> and that it might not ſlip my Memory, I wrote it down about half an hour after. And this leads to the <hi>Fourth</hi> Particular, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That the ſubſtance of his two whole Books, call'd <hi>Memoirs,</hi> &amp;c. are <hi>meer Far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dles of Improbabilities, Incongruities,</hi> and <hi>Invented Falſities.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To Anſwer the whole Books, will be the buſineſs of another time. I ſhall only regard them now <hi>en Paſſant;</hi> I have ſufficiently prov'd, tho he values himſelf upon it, he was not the Author of it, yet to do him a kindneſs, and ſuppoſing it contains his meaning, I ſhall treat it as if it were ſo, without regard to the <hi>diſmal Trunk</hi> he ſpeaks through.</p>
            <p>His Preface, and two firſt Letters to his <hi>Grace,</hi> diſplaies his Quality, tells you <hi>he was of the</hi> Inner-Temple, <hi>and had been Comptroller of that Society,</hi> and then without doubt it was well govern'd. I think that <hi>Dignity</hi> is otherwiſe called <hi>Maſter of Miſrule</hi> at <hi>Chriſtmas;</hi> and ſince his Extravagant Expences upon that Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſion, laid the Foundation of his Ruine, and that the <hi>Office</hi> ſo aptly agrees with the <hi>Rakiſh Qualifications</hi> of the Perſon, I will not grudge him the Honour of it.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:45670:8"/>He was alſo <hi>Captain of an Indepen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant Company.</hi>
               <note n="*">p. 8.</note> 
               <hi>Did Duty at</hi> Windſor-Caſtle, <hi>when His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty came thither upon the Revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lution,</hi> and would Inſinuate that he was <hi>Broke</hi> for no other Reaſon, but becauſe <hi>he had been a Captain in the Late King</hi> James<hi>'s Reign;</hi> but that is a Great Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtake. <hi>He was Broke for being an Er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant Coward.</hi> For the truth of which I appeal to the Noble Lords that <hi>Broke</hi> him. This Paſſage, would admit of ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vere Reflections upon his Honour, <hi>for what will a Coward not be guilty of:</hi> but I will not add to his Afflictions.</p>
            <p>He acknowledges himſelf to be a ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Weak Man, and I find, in running over his Letters, that Natural Imbeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity has had a ſtrange effect upon his <hi>Memory,</hi> as well as his <hi>Courage,</hi> as ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears by the Obſervations following.</p>
            <p>In the 19 and 20 pages, He ſays the <hi>E.</hi> of <hi>P.</hi> next to his Grace the <hi>D.</hi> of <hi>N.</hi> was the firſt Perſon he communicated the Contents of his Letters of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſpondence to, and that this was done in <hi>May</hi> 1696. but he extreamly forgets himſelf, for he ſhew'd them to <hi>Francis Jermy,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> and Mr. <hi>William Read,</hi> at the latter end of <hi>March,</hi> left them three Weeks in his Cuſtody, and put them all
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:45670:8"/>
into my Hands to peruſe on the 23d of <hi>April,</hi> 96.</p>
            <p>He ſays he had no Deſign to Accuſe his Grace the <hi>D.</hi> of <hi>S.</hi> and in page the 26th, out of a tender regard no doubt to his Graces Honour, harrangues ſweet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly upon it in theſe words.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>I could not avoid,</hi> ſays he, <hi>being upon my Oath, to diſcover a Correſpondence be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween a great Miniſter of State and my ſelf. That Honourable Houſe cannot but remember, I anſwered their Queſtions with all the Submiſſion and Profound Reſpect</hi> (Oh Fine Tom. Brown!) <hi>it was poſſible for me to expreſs, in relation to that Noble Peer. I ſaid nothing but what I could not avoid: And I am ſure no reaſonable Man will think me guilty of ſo much Folly, as to believe that I had a Deſign to Accuſe any Perſon, or that I would Deſtroy my Blooming Hopes; for under the Circum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtances I then lay, 'twas not my Intereſt to Oppoſe in the leaſt the Diſpoſitions of the Court.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Poor Man! how he ſtruggles between his Unwillingneſs to accuſe the <hi>D,</hi> and his Tenderneſs of an Oath? This was in <hi>November,</hi> 1696.</p>
            <p>And yet almoſt Eight Months before, that is to ſay, at the beginning of <hi>April</hi> 1696. He told this Story to
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:45670:9"/>
Mr. <hi>Jermy</hi> and Mr. <hi>Read,</hi> and prayed them to <hi>aſſiſt him in making his Complaint to the King againſt his Grace the</hi> D. <hi>of</hi> S.</p>
            <p>And on the 16th and 18th of <hi>April,</hi> 1696. Captain <hi>Smith</hi> in a Publick Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vern near <hi>Charing-Croſs,</hi> in the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of Mr. <hi>Jermy,</hi> M. <hi>William Read</hi> and my Self ſaid, <hi>That he had reaſon to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that the</hi> D. <hi>was in the</hi> Aſſaſſination-Plot, <hi>becauſe he having given him notice of it, his Grace had not acquainted His Majeſty with it, but went out of Town, as he believed, that it might take effect,</hi> and therefore deſired Mr. <hi>Jermy</hi> and my Self, to recommend him to ſome Perſon of Quality near the King, that he might inform His Majeſty, <hi>That by this Great Miniſter's Omiſſion of his Duty, His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty's Life was ſtill in Danger:</hi> Which he aggravated with all his Abilities, and repeated it ſo often, that we were al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt afraid to hear him, tho he was not aſhamed to ſpeak it.</p>
            <p>I ſay <hi>Aſhamed to ſpeak it,</hi> and will leave it to the Readers Judgment whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther I have not authority to ſerve my Self with that Expreſſion; for after two or three meetings, where <hi>the D's con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cealing his Services, and the King's Life being ſtill in Danger,</hi> was the whole ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject of his Diſcourſe; and I having pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſed
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:45670:9"/>
him, if his Letters made it out, to carry him to a <hi>Miniſter</hi> that would repreſent it to the King: I was aſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed upon receiving a Letter from him, contradicting all his confident Affirma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions but a Week before; and I could not forbear thinking, if the Devil owed him a ſhame, he might have took ſome other time to have paid it. The Letter is dated <hi>April</hi> 21. 1696.</p>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>Reverend Sir,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <hi>I</hi> Have for <hi>15</hi> or <hi>16</hi> Months given his Grace the <hi>D.</hi> of <hi>S.</hi> an account of ſuch things as I could by any means obtein the Knowledge of, and have, incloſed, ſent you the Copies of the two laſt Letters <hi>(he ſent me the other Letters</hi> April <hi>19.)</hi> I ſent to him, as being the moſt meterial, they being ſent at the very time the Barbarous Action was to have been committed, and I queſtion not but his Grace made the deſigned uſe of them, and acquainted His Majeſty with the Contents; and by that means pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved His Majeſty's Perſon, and confound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed His Enemies, which was the only thing I aimed at.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>
                        <hi>Your moſt humble Servant</hi> M. Smith.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:45670:10"/>This Letter, under his own Hand Writing, I have by me, ready to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce if their Lordſhips are pleaſed to require it; and think it is a <hi>full</hi> and <hi>ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fectual</hi> Anſwer to both his <hi>Books;</hi> for if they labour with any deſign, except that of diſcovering abundance of <hi>Rude<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs</hi> and <hi>Ill-manners</hi> in the Captain; they contain little elſe, but what he has an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered himſelf, in the above-recited Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, to all Intents and Purpoſes.</p>
            <p>Shewing this Letter to Mr. <hi>Jermy,</hi> who firſt brought the Captain to me, he was very angry with him, ſaying, <hi>What a Vile Fellow he is to Say and Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſay at this Scandalous Rate, and abuſe a Perſon of Quality? When to wipe his Shoes would be an Honour to him.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Not long after ſeeing the Captain in the preſence of Mr. <hi>Jermy</hi> and <hi>W. Read.</hi> I charged him with theſe <hi>Ungentle-man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like Proceedings, in Affirming and Deny<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in Matters of that Importance:</hi> But he thought he excuſed himſelf ſuffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ently by ſaying, <hi>That when he wrote that Letter, a Friend had told him he would reconcile him to the</hi> D. <hi>and put him in hopes of getting him an Allowance; but now,</hi> ſays he, <hi>I ſee I was deluded, and I will go to the King my ſelf, and if he will not hear me, I will appeal to the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:45670:10"/>
where I am promiſed Friends that will do his Buiſineſs for him.</hi> This Diſcourſe was about the 3d of <hi>May,</hi> 1696. by which, and the recited <hi>Letter,</hi> 'tis apparent, that all he Deſigns is his own <hi>Sordid Intereſt.</hi> When he was in expectation from the <hi>D.</hi> then the <hi>D.</hi> did communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate his Services to His <hi>Majeſty.</hi> When he finds nothing coming, then he chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges his Note, and his <hi>Grace</hi> did not do it. Which, to ſay no worſe, is a mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſt Contradiction, and a <hi>Satyr</hi> would have turn'd him out of his <hi>Cell,</hi> as all Mankind ought to do out of their <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany,</hi> for blowing <hi>Hot</hi> and <hi>Cold</hi> with the ſame Breath.</p>
            <p>Till about the middle of <hi>November</hi> following I heard no more of Captain <hi>Smith,</hi> and then he was pleas'd to tell me, Mr. <hi>Jermy</hi> and Mr. <hi>Read, That he had been with the</hi> L. C. <hi>the</hi> E. <hi>of</hi> A. <hi>the</hi> E. <hi>of</hi> P—h <hi>and Sir</hi> W. T. <hi>that they had promiſed him a Penſion of Four Thouſand Pounds a Year; but he mould not accept it without a</hi> Conſiderable Title. <hi>He knew they intended to make him a</hi> Lord, <hi>but he ſcorned to accept of any thing below a</hi> Duke. This Relation will appear ſtrange to thoſe that know him not; but if any Man of Conſideration ſeems to queſtion the Truth of it, they may
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:45670:11"/>
when they pleaſe have it confirmed un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Oathes of the three Gentlemen above-named.</p>
            <p>But while we were expecting the Iſſue of this <hi>bold</hi> adventure, we were told that our Captain's <hi>Blooming Hopes</hi> were <hi>Froſt-bitten.</hi> It ſeems they knew him better at <hi>Kenſington</hi> than he knew him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, <hi>and diſcharg'd him from appearing any more at Court:</hi> And ſoon after, as he ſays himſelf, <hi>all his Friends dropt him,</hi> and I fear thoſe that took him up ſince, and made him a <hi>Property</hi> to ſerve their own Deſigns, will e're long deſert him alſo; for that commonly is the fatal con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequence of depending on, and ſerving the Intereſt of a Party.</p>
            <p>His <hi>Rappers</hi> are ſo thick ſowed, and grown ſo <hi>Rank</hi> through his whole Books, that I muſt content my Reader at preſent only with a few Gleaning, till the whole Crop is fit for Threſhing out, and then he ſhall have a large Amends. The Captain ſays, that <hi>Holmes,</hi> a Proclamation-man, lay with him one Nigt, when the Government was in ſearch of him; but he <hi>generouſly</hi> ſuffer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed him to eſcape in the Morning. <hi>I hope the Captain does not Reckon that Neglect, among the number of his Services;</hi> but what is more ſtrange, he would not
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:45670:11"/>
               <hi>earn the Thouſand Pound Reward for ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king him, becauſe he mould not betray any Body for Money.</hi> Bravely ſpoken, but who can believe it, that conſiders how he paid his <hi>Dear Reſpects to his Unkle,</hi> and there are Men of Honour that have known his Converſation from his Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ventry Cradle, that are of Opinion, <hi>The Captain would have Hang'd his — for half the Money.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To prove his ability to ſerve the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, inſtead of Firm-ground, he lays hold on two ſlender <hi>Reeds,</hi> which are too weak to bear the weight he lays upon them; and yet upon examining, are ſtrong enough to wound his Credit, and deſtroy all his pretenſion to <hi>Merit</hi> from them.</p>
            <p>His Topping Inſtance is from his <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timacy</hi> and <hi>Intereſt</hi> in one Mr. <hi>John Hewet,</hi> who was employed by certain <hi>Jacobites</hi> to deliver their Forreign and Inland Letters, when they durſt not truſt them by the Common Convenien<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies.</p>
            <p>The Captain has truly deſcribed his pretended Correſpondents Employment, but trifles and impoſes upon the Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, when to make his Intelligence ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>appear more conſiderable then it was; he is forced to ſet him up for a <hi>Gentleman.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:45670:12"/>
               <hi>John Hewet</hi> was a <hi>Poor Lad,</hi> kept up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Charity, and the <hi>Jacobites</hi> experien<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cing his Fidelity, truſted him with the Delivery of their Letters; but for the Captain to pretend to an Intereſt in that <hi>Boy,</hi> and in ſix or ſeven Months time to make no better uſe of him; is to ſay he had undertaken a Province he knew not how to manage, or in truth that he had no Intereſt at all in him. Had there been ſuch an Intire <hi>Truſt</hi> and <hi>Confidence</hi> between the <hi>Boy</hi> and the <hi>Captain,</hi> as he pretends to: <hi>Jack Hewet</hi> was able moſt Weeks in the Year, and almoſt every Day in the Week, to have put a Pac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quet of Letters into the Captains Hands, that being <hi>Diſcreetly Managed,</hi> might have been ſafely returned to <hi>Hewet,</hi> and afterwards have been delivered by him as directed, without the leaſt ſuſpicion that they had been opened. Such a <hi>ſmart touch as this</hi> had been <hi>ſervice in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed,</hi> and deſervedly would have made the Captains <hi>Fortune;</hi> but ſince this was every day in the <hi>Bov</hi>'s power, and he would not oblige the Captain with it, there is no reaſon to believe that the <hi>Boy</hi> would truſt him with a greater matter, and what in all probability he was not truſted with himſelf; for none but Fools and Madmen, would put ſo
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:45670:12"/>
many Lives into the Hands of a <hi>Lad but of</hi> 13 <hi>Years of Age.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But that which puts an End to the Captains Pretence of Correſponding with <hi>Hewet,</hi> is, That <hi>John Hewet</hi> being Interrogated upon Oath by the Lords in Parliament, declared, <hi>That he never Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quainted Captain</hi> Smith <hi>with any of the</hi> Jacobites <hi>Secrets; but finding him Inqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitive, and Prodigal of his Money, he col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected News out of the</hi> Poſt-Boy <hi>to get ſome Money from him, under pretence that it came from</hi> France.</p>
            <p>Captain <hi>Smith</hi> was preſent when the <hi>Lad</hi> made this Oath; and as he made no Anſwer to it then, neither has he at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempted to diſprove it in his <hi>Memoirs,</hi> tho' he has impertinently waſted 14 Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, in giving Reaſons why he Corre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſponded with <hi>Hewet;</hi> when <hi>Hewet</hi> has Sworn <hi>he never Correſponded with him.</hi> The Competition and Credibility is to the Captain's Diſadvantage; the <hi>Lad</hi> is upon his Oath, and the Captain but on his Honour. The Captain aſſiſts the Boy with an <hi>Excellent</hi> Character, and ſo gives him Credit againſt himſelf; but neither the <hi>Lad,</hi> nor no Body elſe that know him, will beſtow one <hi>favourable Word</hi> upon the Captain. So that Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence is vaniſhed.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:45670:13"/>His next Aſſylum, or Argument to prove himſelf capable of diſcovering the moſt Secret Caballings, and cloſeſt De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigns of His Majeſty's Enemies: Nay, if he might be ſupplied with as much Money as he wanted, <hi>That it ſhould be utterly impoſſible for any thing, either Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign, or Domeſtick, to eſcape his knowledge,</hi> was, becauſe <hi>Sir</hi> William Parkins, <hi>one of the Chiefs of the</hi> Jacobite <hi>Party was his Unkle, and not only truſted him with his choiceſt Secrets, but employed him to Court other Men to aſſiſt in the Deſign, take Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſions under him;</hi> and I know not how many other Good-Morrows, as <hi>Incredi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble</hi> as his refuſing to get a <hi>Thouſand Pounds</hi> upon a Point of Honour!</p>
            <p>The bare recital of theſe Improbabili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, as they are apparent in his <hi>Memoirs,</hi> naturally lead me to ask Captain <hi>Smith</hi> a few ſhort Queſtions?</p>
            <p>What neceſſity was there to be at ſo much Charge in Correſponding with <hi>Hewet,</hi> when Sir <hi>William Parkins</hi> was ſo Free with him, that was no Stranger to all their Deſigns?</p>
            <p>What made him ignorant of <hi>the Day</hi> when the Treaſon was to be acted, ſince all the Conſpirators knew of it above a Fortnight before?</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="25" facs="tcp:45670:13"/>Why was he not more <hi>Plain</hi> and <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular</hi> in his Letters to my Lord D, when his <hi>Grace</hi> and Mr. <hi>V.</hi> ſo often de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſired it? There is no queſtion to be made but Sir <hi>William Parkins</hi> could have fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh'd him with the whole Matter, and there can be no excuſe for his Non-com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyance with his Grace's repeated Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands, but that either the Captain for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>got to ask his Unkle, <hi>and then he negle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted his Buſineſs:</hi> Or, that Sir <hi>William Parkins</hi> could not tell him, <hi>and then no Body will believe him:</hi> Or that Sir <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> would not tell him, and then 'tis plain <hi>he would not truſt him;</hi> ſo that take it which way you pleaſe, it looks with an ill Face upon the Captain, and he would do well to lay his <hi>Services</hi> a little cloſer together for the future.</p>
            <p>Among other Names that he gives us a Catalogue of, as his Acquaintance a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong the Quondam <hi>Jacobites,</hi> he is plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed unluckily to mention Captain <hi>Porter:</hi> Let us hear what that Gentleman is plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to ſay in the Matter, whom the worſt of his Enemies never accus'd for prevaricating in any thing relating to that whole Conſpiracy.</p>
            <p>About a Fortnight, or thereabouts, ſince, having an Opportunity to Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe Captain <hi>Porter,</hi> I took the Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:45670:14"/>
to ask him, Whether he knew of any <hi>Correſpondence and Truſt between Sir</hi> William Parkins <hi>and his Nephew Captain</hi> Matthew Smith? <hi>Captain</hi> Porter <hi>was plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> Anſwer,</p>
            <p>That once, and no oftner, as he could remember, Captain <hi>Smith</hi> came into a Room where Sir <hi>William Parkins,</hi> Him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, and others, were in Conſultation upon their Buſineſs: Captain <hi>Smith</hi> was no ſooner ſat down, but by a private Intimation from Sir <hi>William Parkins,</hi> they drop'd the Subject they were diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſing on, and fell a talking about a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother Buſineſs: And when Captain <hi>Smith</hi> left the Room, Sir <hi>William Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kins</hi> took that Advantage, <hi>To forewarn his Friends that were preſent from keeping Capt.</hi> Smith <hi>Company, or Diſcourſing any of their Matters before him.</hi> 'Tis true, ſays Sir <hi>William,</hi> I Married his Aunt, and therefore am obliged to be common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Civil to him; <hi>But pray have a care of him. He is a — and a Fellow that I never truſted.</hi> This Relation, upon my Requeſt, Captain <hi>Forter</hi> was pleaſed to give me leave, if I thought fit, to Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh in his Name, and he would own it. And after this, he that can believe any thing that <hi>Smith</hi> ſays will boggle at nothing.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="27" facs="tcp:45670:14"/>Another Witty Gentleman, and of great Integrity and Honour, that is no Stranger to Capt. <hi>Smith,</hi> who will quick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly tell you his Name, tho' I am oblig'd to conceal it, told me he knew Captain <hi>Smith was the utter Averſion of Sir</hi> Willi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>am Parkins, <hi>the Scorn of the whole Family, and never fit to be truſted with any thing that he could Tell, Sell, or Pawn for</hi> 6 <hi>Pence.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>He pretends to an Acquaintance with <hi>Capt. Boys,</hi> who was ſome time in the Counſels of the <hi>Jacobite</hi> Party. I ask'd that Gentleman what Intereſt Capt. <hi>Smith</hi> had among them; but he averr'd <hi>he ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver knew him.</hi> He is ſafe in naming the reſt of his pretended Correſpondents a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong the <hi>Jacobeans;</hi> for they are all ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Dead or Baniſhed <hi>England;</hi> or there is no reaſon to doubt but they would con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm the Opinion of his being a moſt No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torious <hi>Romancer.</hi> In ſhort,</p>
            <p>All his Pretences to do Service for the Government, were but <hi>Tricks</hi> to ſupply a <hi>Boundleſs Extravagancy.</hi> He was dri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven to his <hi>laſt Shift,</hi> his Inventions were upon the Wrack how to <hi>ſubſiſt;</hi> and his Relation to Sir <hi>William Parkins</hi> giving him a Colour to impoſe upon the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, he reſolves to make the ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt <hi>Penny</hi> of it, Trumps it up upon all Occaſions, and keeps up his Correſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:45670:15"/>
with the Duke by <hi>repeated Promi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes</hi> what he could and would do from that Relation, while he did nothing but abuſe and delay his Grace upon thoſe Pretences, which, in truth, had Colour enough to deceive any Man.</p>
            <p>He makes no Pretences to be qualifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for this Employment by vertue of his <hi>Underſtanding,</hi> and <hi>Sincerity,</hi> which is the Wiſeſt Thing he ever diſcovered; for all that have known him from his Birth, till he ſet up for a <hi>Memoirer</hi> and <hi>Remarker,</hi> are ſenſible he never carried any ſuch things about him: And I am not ſo much ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prized, to find him ſo early diſcarded by the D, as I admire it was not done 12 Months ſooner; but this muſt be aſcri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bed to his <hi>Plying</hi> the D. with large Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes in every Letter, and his Grace's Unwillingneſs to neglect any Opportu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity of ſerving the Government, where there was ſuch a plauſible Pretence as <hi>Smith</hi> laid hold on to ſerve himſelf, and abuſe the D's Candor and Credulity by Falſe Inſinuations. However do but</p>
            <p>Read all the D's Letters to our Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain: See the Encouragements he gave him, if he could do Service, and if you don't diſcover in his <hi>Grace</hi> a continued Series of <hi>Uneaſineſs</hi> and <hi>Suſpicion</hi> of the Author's Veracity, as well he might
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:45670:15"/>
from his <hi>Arguing,</hi> inſtead of <hi>Infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming,</hi> which only was his Duty; from his Stuffing his Letters with <hi>Impertinent Traſh,</hi> and <hi>Idle Stories,</hi> inſtead of Real Services, and his promiſing many Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coveries, and at beſt giving but a <hi>Dark ſight</hi> into any thing, I will forfeit my Judgment. I have already ſhew'd what <hi>Tricks</hi> have been play'd with his <hi>Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters,</hi> and now think it material to add, and I undertake to prove it by Credible Witneſſes,</p>
            <p>
               <hi>That before he delivered out any Copies of his Letters, he knew from a Good Hand, That his Original Letters ſent to the D, were loſt:</hi> And then what might not a Man of his Principles do, to ſupport his own Pretenſions.</p>
            <p>Another thing the Captain makes a Noiſe with, is the <hi>Merits of his Service;</hi> which can only be known by his Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters: And tho' I have ſaid enough to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>validate the whole, by the Tricks that he has play'd with them, and the Suſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cion that lies upon them all, by his know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the <hi>Originals were loſt,</hi> yet let any unprejudiced Eye View them in the Dreſs they now appear in, without the <hi>Sham</hi> and <hi>Trick</hi> of <hi>Language, Ornament, and Dreſs,</hi> pretended <hi>Private Diſcourſes, Minutes, Notes,</hi> and <hi>Obſervations,</hi> which
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:45670:16"/>
have no other Authority to give them Credit, but the empty Flouriſhes of the <hi>Poet</hi>'s Fruitful Brain, to Earn the Sum of <hi>Threeſcore Pounds,</hi> and the Naked Affir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation of a <hi>Profligate Wretch,</hi> to gain <hi>Four Thouſand Pounds a Year and a Duke<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom</hi> by his Services; and if he diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers any thing in them but <hi>Impertinent Chat, Nauſeous trifling with a Miniſter of State, and dim Diſcoveries,</hi> he has a clear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er Eye-ſight and Underſtanding than o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Men dare pretend to.</p>
            <p>This brings me to take a View of his Second Book, Entituled, <hi>Remarks upon the D. of S—'s Letter to the Houſe of Lords, concerning Captain</hi> Smith; <hi>being a Vindication of his Services,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>A general Survey of theſe Remarks, without Animadverting upon particular Inſtances, is enough to Nauſeate any <hi>Modeſt</hi> Reader; for in no one Line have they treated that <hi>Truly Great Perſon</hi> like a Gentleman, for which the Infamous <hi>Poet</hi> is as much to be ſcorn'd, as the Malicious Captain, and their <hi>Suppor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters</hi> and <hi>Managers.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Every Page is ſo beſmeered with <hi>Sor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>did</hi> Clownery, <hi>Saucy</hi> Language, and <hi>Impudent Reflections,</hi> that would ſhame any Pen, tho' made of <hi>Braſs;</hi> or any Men, but ſuch a Couple of Contempti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:45670:16"/>
               <hi>Wretches,</hi> as have club'd their Nod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dles to render themſelves Ridiculous, and Puniſhable. There is too much in theſe <hi>Remarks</hi> to be confuted, almoſt e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Line may be diſproved, or ought to be <hi>Reprehended,</hi> they are well nigh <hi>Burſting</hi> with <hi>Stinging Wind,</hi> ſuch as the <hi>Hackney</hi> Jade <hi>Pegaſus</hi> lets fly when he is too hard Girt upon a full Belly.</p>
            <p>They are nothing but Idle and Imper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinent <hi>Repetitions</hi> of his <hi>Memoirs,</hi> which being anſwer'd already, I might have ſlighted for that reaſon; but ſince Mr. <hi>Brown,</hi> after all his ſeeming <hi>Penitential Sorrow, crying Peccavi, and begging Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don for his firſt Offence in employing his Pen to ſo Baſe a Purpoſe,</hi> has aggrava<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted his Crime by relapſing into his for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer Faults and Follies, which no Body will wonder at that knows his Chara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cter, give me leave to gueſs at the Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſion of it, and give them both a ſhort Anſwer.</p>
            <p>Our <hi>Hackney</hi> Imp of <hi>Parnaſſus,</hi> that all the Vacation ſtands at Livery to be Ridden by every Malicious Fop; being extreamly out of <hi>Sorts,</hi> as it often hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pens by his <hi>Idleneſs</hi> and <hi>Debauchery,</hi> and reduced to the true State of a <hi>Heathen Philoſopher:</hi> The Riding-Coat that <hi>Smith</hi> gave him when they were <hi>Memoiring,</hi>
               <pb n="32" facs="tcp:45670:17"/>
being wore Thredbare, and his whole Man calling for Amendments, for fear of falling into the Rag-Man's Hands, for want of Reparations; he once more, to his Shame, engages with <hi>Smith,</hi> and all on a ſudden <hi>Tom Brown</hi> appears New Rig'd from <hi>Stem</hi> to <hi>Stern;</hi> and immediately after, out comes theſe Remarks to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaint the Town who was the Author of them.</p>
            <p>The Captain puts his <hi>Name</hi> to the Pamphlet, and 'tis flouriſh'd with a Quo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation out of <hi>Virgil.</hi> I cannot but won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der at his Confidence, in pauming him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf upon the World for a Man of <hi>Learn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,</hi> when he is ſo Notoriouſly known to be one of the greateſt Dunces in Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture; who if he was to Faſt till he could Conſtrue ſo many Words in <hi>Latin,</hi> or Write any three Lines in the whole <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>marks,</hi> would certainly Die of Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger:</p>
            <p>But he has ſo long accuſtomed himſelf to claim the Honour of Services <hi>he never did;</hi> that it's now grown into a Habit, and he cannot leave it: Tho' by his good Favour it lays an indelible Blot up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on his Reputation: For he that <hi>for no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing</hi> has Forehead enough to own a Book that not one Line of it his own, What will he not do when Four Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:45670:17"/>
Pounds a Year, and a Conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble <hi>Title</hi> is to be the Purchaſe of his <hi>Leaſing?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I confeſs, the Remarks are worded to the beſt Advantage of ſo ill a Cauſe. The <hi>Poet</hi> has ſhew'd his great Abilities in the Black Art of Scandal, and trick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing up other Peoples <hi>Malice</hi> into a gau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy Dreſs of Words, to delude the Vul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gar Readers into a good Opinion of what he is advancing. How eaſie a Matter this is for a Man of Parts to do, that gives himſelf a Looſe into the Common Place of Railery, without confining him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf to the Laws of <hi>Truth,</hi> or the Rules of <hi>Decency</hi> and <hi>Good Manners,</hi> is very in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>telligible to Men of Sence: They both abhor the Practice and make allowance for it; while the meaner ſort are capti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vated by the <hi>Stile,</hi> and led Blindfold in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Error. I ſhall therefore diſappoint the latter, and I hope, oblige the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer by anſwering Matter of <hi>Fact</hi> only, without being at the trouble to remove the Rubbiſh and Trumpery that enclo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes it.</p>
            <p>The Preface acquaints us <hi>how provok<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a thing it is to a Man of any Spirit to be treated with Contempt;</hi> which I ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe is no new thing to him, and he has no reaſon to be in ſuch a <hi>Chafe,</hi> or <hi>Paſſion</hi>
               <pb n="34" facs="tcp:45670:18"/>
about it; ſince he never was, nor de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved to be treated otherwiſe.</p>
            <p>He is ambitious, you ſee, all along of a <hi>Conſiderable Title,</hi> and yet is an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gry that his Adverſaries have found a fit one for him, viz. <hi>Fool or Madman,</hi> tho others are of opinion, he has ſo great an Alloy of the former in his Conſtitution, that he is in no danger of falling under the denomination of the latter: Nor will they allow it con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferr'd upon him by the Malice of his <hi>Enemies,</hi> ſince it has been the whole ſtudy of his Life to acquire the <hi>Title.</hi> They are pleas'd, as a Specimen of their Good Manners, to join <hi>Quality</hi> with <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolence,</hi> which is an Argument the <hi>Dung-Hill</hi> and the <hi>Tann-Fat</hi> lay too near both their Fathers Doors, for either of them to pretend to be Gentlemen. How might I expatiate on ſo fruitful a Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject; but I hate to be thought a Trifler.</p>
            <p>He runs on with the old ſtory of <hi>Stifling</hi> and <hi>Deprecicating</hi> his Services, which methinks 'tis now high time to give over, ſince with all the Intereſt he has with a <hi>Party</hi> to aſſiſt him, he could never perſuade any body to believe, that <hi>he has done any Service but what he has been very well paid for;</hi> and his bold demanding and threatning for more, has
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:45670:18"/>
made him ſlighted and deſpiſed by eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry body.</p>
            <p>His Inſolent behaviour at <hi>Kenſington,</hi> cauſed him to be diſcharged the Court. Tho he gave away ſome hundreds of his Books among the Honourable the Houſe of Commons, he could not find one <hi>Member</hi> that would deliver his <hi>Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tition</hi> to the <hi>Houſe.</hi> He has addreſt to the Right Honourable the Houſe of <hi>Peers;</hi> and their Lordſhips have com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded his Book of <hi>Remarks</hi> to <hi>be burnt by the Hand of the Common Hang<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man.</hi> Whither will he go next? Are not the <hi>King, Lords</hi> nor <hi>Commons</hi> Able to Judge of the Merits of his Service! Had he Wit to his Malice, and Power to his Venom, he would ſet the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom in a Flame.</p>
            <p>I will next proceed to his Grievances, and the Firſt that preſents it ſelf is a Complaint, <hi>That he was taken up by a Meſſenger when the Plot was warm;</hi> and this he conſtrues as <hi>a Deſign upon his Perſon and Papers;</hi> when any thing, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides himſelf, would have known, that it was to comply with his Requeſt of being <hi>concealed,</hi> that they did it, tho they would not truſt him with the Reaſon why they did it. Had he any harder meaſure than others under his Circum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtances?
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:45670:19"/>
Was not Sir <hi>Thomas Pendergarſt</hi> and Mr. <hi>La Rue,</hi> that were the Firſt Diſcoverers of the <hi>Aſſaſſination-Plot,</hi> ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken up and committed? Was not Mr. <hi>Fiſher</hi> and Mr. <hi>Grimes</hi> that knew more of the Plot than the Captain can ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſtly pretend to, taken up by Meſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers, and kept ſometime Priſoners in their Houſes? Is there not many Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons to be given for theſe Prudent Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings? Well! in ſome colder Cly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate 'tis poſſible our Doughty Captain may come to great Military Preferment; but certainly his Head is not long enough to make a States-man.</p>
            <p>In his next Complaint he Fights in the <hi>Dark,</hi> and gives us an unaccountable Stretch of his <hi>Talent. Some Body</hi> (he leaves the Reader to Gueſs who) he ſays, <hi>ſuppreſt Sir</hi> William Parkin's <hi>Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, which after the ineffectual Applica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Houſe of Commons,</hi> pray ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve it, <hi>I had,</hi> ſays he, <hi>the Fortune to prevail with him to make.</hi> What an in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>credible Story have we here? That af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Honourable Members of the Houſe of Commons, that viſited Sir <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> in <hi>Newgate,</hi> could not prevail with him to make a <hi>Confeſſion;</hi> yet our Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, that was his <hi>utter Averſion,</hi> effect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed it. Can any Man in his Right Mind,
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:45670:19"/>
imagine that Sir <hi>William Parkins</hi> was ſo void of Senſe, to believe that <hi>Smith</hi> could more effectually prevail with the King to Pardon him, than a Whole Houſe of Commons! Away Captain! This <hi>Remark</hi> lies ſo Wide, and Broad, 'tis impoſſible to ſwallow it without Choaking. Farther, he ſays,</p>
            <p>The Lady <hi>Parkins</hi> went to <hi>Kenſing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton</hi> to give a Petition to his Grace the the <hi>D.</hi> of <hi>N.</hi> to deliver to His Majeſty. His Grace had prepared the King to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive it; was expected; the <hi>D.</hi> of <hi>N.</hi> ſent to enquire for the Lady <hi>Parkins;</hi> ſhe was not to be found: <hi>yet a certain Perſon,</hi> without ſo much as a Letter to Gueſs at his Name or Quality, found her, when no body elſe could, and ſent the Lady away full of Sorrow and Deſpair, aſſuring her it would not be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived. There is little Reaſon to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve the Lady would take her Anſwer from any Perſon, but the <hi>D.</hi> of <hi>N.</hi> who had promiſed to deliver it, nor that any <hi>Certain Perſon</hi> would ſuppreſs a Petition <hi>that His Majeſty expected.</hi> When <hi>Smith</hi> told this Story firſt, he laid the Blame upon the <hi>Lady for not coming to Kenſing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton till the Council was up, and gone, and the King retir'd into His Bedchamber,</hi> tho now he lays it upon a <hi>Certain Perſon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:45670:20"/>His Invention is ſo <hi>Barren,</hi> and he is at ſo great a Loſs for New Matter, that he is forced to harp upon the ſame Strings in his <hi>Remarks,</hi> that he had before al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt fretted to pieces, by his nauſeous Repetitions in his <hi>Memoirs:</hi> His Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt in <hi>Hewet</hi> and Sir <hi>William Parkins</hi> is ſtill the Burden of the Song; and yet neither in his former nor latter Book takes he any Notice, that <hi>Hewet has deny'd it upon Oath,</hi> and that Sir <hi>Willi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>am</hi> has <hi>branded</hi> him with a <hi>Hard Name,</hi> and diſcharged <hi>the whole Party from truſting him with the Knowledge of their Matters;</hi> for tho he was his Wifes Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation, he knew him <hi>too well</hi> to repoſe any Confidence in him.</p>
            <p>To magnifie his own Intelligence, through both his Books, he underva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lues the diſcovery of Sir <hi>Thomas Pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dergarſt</hi> and Mr. <hi>La Rue,</hi> tho the whole Nation is ſatisfied with their Candor and Sincerity in the whole Affair.</p>
            <p>Upon this Head he has ſo remarka<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble a piece of <hi>Effrontery,</hi> that I cannot paſs it over without admiring at his Confidence, in ſetting up himſelf for a common Calumniator, and one that ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver <hi>Starts</hi> in publiſhing the moſt Noto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious <hi>Falſhoods</hi> in the World: Such as every Eye can diſcover, and every Man
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:45670:20"/>
detect that hath read any thing in theſe Proceedings. He was ignorant <hi>of the Day on which His Majeſty was to be Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered,</hi> and therefore would perſuade the Reader, <hi>that the Conſpirators themſelves did not know it;</hi> tho you may read it in all the Tryals upon Oath, <hi>that the Day was appointed before the Date of his Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters to the Duke;</hi> and all that were to be Actors in were enjoyn'd to be ready on it. But this is not what I principal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly intended, but that which follows.</p>
            <p>In Page the Eighth he has theſe Words, <hi>Whoever will take the pains to compare the Evidences of Captain</hi> Porter <hi>and Mr.</hi> Pendergarſt <hi>with my Memoirs, will find there a ſufficient Confirmation of every Tittle, that I ſay: Tho he will plainly ſee, that</hi> They <hi>were even then but half informed of thoſe things which I had long before fully diſcovered.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>There might be ſome pretence for his ſaying he knew more of the <hi>Plot,</hi> and before Sir <hi>Thomas Pendergarſt</hi> did, whom Captain <hi>Porter</hi> ſent for to Town, but a little before the Treaſon was to be put in Execution; but to ſay he knew it ſooner, and better than Captain <hi>Porter,</hi> is to tell the World, that if he has any Conſcience, 'tis ſo Caſe-hardened it will boggle at nothing, and that Beel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zebub
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:45670:21"/>
would <hi>Keck</hi> at a Story that Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain <hi>Smith</hi> makes no Scruple at. Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain <hi>Porter</hi> and Sir <hi>William</hi> were Hand and Glove in the whole <hi>Conſpiracy,</hi> and mutually correſponded in every Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumſtance. <hi>Smith</hi> does not pretend to have the Diſcovery of this <hi>Plot</hi> from Sir <hi>William,</hi> but from <hi>Jack Hewet;</hi> and in ſhort, <hi>Smith</hi> would perſuade us, that <hi>Jack Hewet</hi> knew more of the <hi>Aſſaſſina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion-Plot</hi> than either Sir <hi>W. P.</hi> or Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain <hi>Porter.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>He ſays his <hi>Grace</hi> knew <hi>what he was, and what he is, before he had any Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſpondence with</hi> that Noble Peer: I have no Faith in that <hi>Article,</hi> but on the contrary am of Opinion, that if his <hi>Grace</hi> had known <hi>Smith</hi>'s Veritable Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racter, he would have diſmiſt him much ſooner than he did; tho his <hi>Grace</hi> could not have done it ſo early as he deſerved it. However, ſince he values himſelf upon <hi>being known</hi> to the D. that he may not give himſelf any further trouble in publiſhing his own Hiſtory, a Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man has undertaken to <hi>write his Life,</hi> and then every Body may know him alſo.</p>
            <p>The next thing he makes a Noiſe with, is the <hi>Merits of his Services;</hi> but ſince he is unable to value them him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf,
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:45670:21"/>
what Expectations can he have from a <hi>Subject,</hi> when his Demands are ſo extraordinary, that he <hi>ſcorns</hi> Four Thouſand Pound a Year, unleſs one of the moſt <hi>Conſiderable Titles</hi> of Honour in the Kingdom be Tack'd to his <hi>Squireſhip.</hi> But to ballance the Account. He ſerv'd in <hi>Secret Service</hi> as he calls it, after he has made the whole Nation Ring of it) <hi>full Seventeen Months,</hi> his <hi>Grand Tour</hi> beyond Sea being thrown into the Scale to make Weight, for which he acknowledges to have recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved from His Majeſty above <hi>Three Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pounds;</hi> which if the Proper Judges had not thought ſufficient, there is no Queſtion but he would have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived (if he had known how to ask it) a further Compenſation; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he ought to have been determin'd by them. This was paid above-board; but when the Captain and I am at lei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure, to a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>unt for all the Sums of Money he <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>as clandeſtinely received from <hi>the Party that Fool'd him into be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing an Author,</hi> it will ſurprize the Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to hear there was ſo much miſchief carried on, under ſo <hi>Thin and Mean a Cover.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To Conclude. In his <hi>Memoirs,</hi> he ſays, <hi>he never complain'd of his Grace.</hi>
               <pb n="42" facs="tcp:45670:22"/>
In page the 15th of his <hi>Remarks</hi> he ſays, <hi>he did complain of him, and that he had reaſon for it, but that he did it in an Unhandſome manner, or threatned to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plain of him in Parliament, he utterly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies.</hi> And,</p>
            <p>Yet as confidently, as he denies it, it will be prov'd upon the Oathes of Three Witneſſes, (when ever required) <hi>that he did do it, and that very Unhand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſomely too,</hi> as you will find immedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ately.</p>
            <p>After aſſerting ſo notorious a Falſity, he Wonders <hi>that his Grace ſhould think it neither Safe, nor Decent, to have any more to do with him,</hi> and ſays, <hi>'tis a My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery that none but the D. can unfold;</hi> but for once, and uſe it not, without trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bling his <hi>Grace,</hi> I will be the Captains <hi>Oedipus,</hi> and, in ſhort, am ready to produce the Perſon, that in <hi>April,</hi> 1696. told his Grace at his Houſe, in St. <hi>James</hi>'s Square, <hi>that Captain Matthew Smith</hi> in a Tavern near <hi>Charing-Croſs,</hi> in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of <hi>Francis Jermy,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Mr. <hi>Willi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>am Read</hi> and the Author, <hi>did vilely a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buſe his Grace in a very reproachful Lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guage, and ſaid he would complain of his Grace to the King; and if His Majeſty would not hear him, he would complain againſt him the next Parliament, where he
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:45670:22"/>
was promis'd the Aſſiſtance of Friends that would do his Buſineſs for him.</hi> And after this I preſume neither the Captain, nor no Body elſe, will wonder at his Graces Future Conduct toward him: Who is ſo <hi>Falſe</hi> and <hi>Vain</hi> a Creature, then when his Book was <hi>Printing,</hi> and he upon the <hi>Pinn</hi> of commending his own <hi>Politicks,</hi> he ſaid in the preſence of two <hi>Reputable Citizens, That it was in his Power either to Preſerve or Ruine the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Government at his Pleaſure;</hi> with other like <hi>Rhodomontades,</hi> that I am both afraid, and aſhamed to Publiſh.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
